HABTESELASSIE BIRUK YEMANE

Front-end Developer

Address:
Pekankatu 5, Helsinki
Phone:
+358465406969
Email:
bir_yem@yahoo.com

Profile

I have worked on various projects developing web applications using various frameworks and tools. Recently, though, my focus has been directed towards modern front-end development. I have experience building single page applications(SPAs) using React. I'm now interested in modern front-end development using state-of-the-art frameworks and JavaScript build tools.

Github · Linkedin

Education

Master of Science: **Software Development** - 2017 **University of Tampere**, Finland

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science - 2008 HiLCoE School of Computer Science, Ethiopia

Skill Highlights

Script - JavaScript/ES6
Framework - React
State management - Redux, Redux Saga
Build tools - Node, NPM, Yarn, webPack, Babel
Styling - CSS3, Flexbox, media queries
UI/UX - Material UI, reactstrap, Responsive design
Testing - Jest, Mocha, Sinon, Chai

Experience

Front-end Developer - 04/2020 to present X-Team

- I work front-end projects focusing on React
- Cooperate with designers to create and implement clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.

Full-stack Developer - 06/2019 to 03/2020 Priceff, Helsinki

- Develop features to the React frontend
- Develop and run test suites to ensure the quality of the service
- Develop Shopify app using Shopify's React component library
- Develop new APIs and improve the AWS Lambda Node.js backend

Junior web Developer - 08/2018 to 07/2019 **Integrify**, Helsinki

- Member of Integrify's 6-month state-of-the-art software developer mentoring program learning modern software development. The focus is JavaScript, React/Redux, Node and Express.
- Teaching led by experienced software developers every day, resulting in up to 1000 hours of coding.

Web Developer - 06/2008 to 05/2012 **eSystems Africa**, Ethiopia

 I applied a wide breadth of technical skills and experience across the Spectrum of online development in the service of building and improving online properties for multiple clients. I used open source toolset and also Microsoft technologies.

Solving coding problems - 04/2019 to Present **Hackerrank**

• I do it mainly for fun but also to develop my skills.